J Campell you come up Jan Campbell
serves as the 56th and first female and
still only female mayor ofand 2003 to
January
2006 her bio goes on and on but prior to
elected office Mayor Jane held
leadership roles with several Community
organizations and advocacy groups for
example in 1975 she founded women's
space she worked as National Field
director for ER americ Washington DC she
served in the Ohio House of
Representatives multiple times
K commission I'm still going to read it
though we can go on on with mayor G but
some for efforts as mayor included work
toward the lakefront plan Steel Yard
Commons Gordon Square Arts District Four
Street Redevelopment and ID Avenue Rapid
Transit
Corridor in August 2003 mayor Campbell
led a US delegation to AEL that ammended
the Deep ties and comter roots in the
official ceremony in castlebar the
official tning of a Cleveland the place
as a result of Steve Malloy Terence dber
and mayor Jame
[Applause]
Campbell
okay I feel like we should have like a
seventh in stretch or something I figure
now everybody here is either related to
somebody on the stage or work for me
right thank you very much for your
patience and for inviting me to be part
of this festivity
uh it is risky risky to invite a
politician uh even a former politician
to this stage just because each of the
people who are here I had a story about
now I was going to tell the story about
Dick po telling me that he was not going
to support me for mayor because he was
supporting Mary Rose o car and told the
same story I mean this was not good
because that was my line I don't
appreciate it
uh did us when television was
dignified I mean
really ship we had some stories about
the colinwood community center didn't we
and to keep that keep those Cent going
and the work that you've done thank you
so much Bishop Hill was the bishop
during all the time when I was serving
in public office and so there are so
many times when you turn to the bishop
even if you're not Catholic because of
his leadership role and there two times
that I remember very well on September
11th when the planes hit and we didn't
really know what was happening I was
commissioner I was running for mayor we
were in this alphabetical race that was
when I was running against Mary Rose
that was campaigning against
me we we really didn't know what to do
and Bishop pill had mass and we all but
I said let's just go to mass and I took
this group of people not a single one of
them was c um and the only place where
we could feel things were right was
listening to Bishop pill that
morning Jose being away have we Campaign
together stories and tales uh we have
Campaign together together and he has
been an incredible advocate for the
Hispanic community and you think the
stories they tell you he nothing like
that behind the scenes he's more intense
and more Dynamic so I'm not here to talk
about the rest of the abues I'm here to
tell you about Steve
mooy and Steve
mooy the warmth of Steve malloy's
personality would fill this
room many of his family members are here
his beloved wife Annie is here I want
all of the to stand
up and
extended Che it's only it's only a small
portion of all of the LA there are many
many
Mallo Steve
mooy
is still to this day in my mind a force
of
major he had it in his
mind that Cleveland was going to have a
twin with County Mayo and with that and
he was not going to let that go and he
was determined to make it
happen and you've heard people talk
about each of the inductees and their
commitment to Faith their commitment to
family and their commitment to their
country of origin and their adopted
country well Steve had all that in
addition he had a commitment to local
310 which was his Union family which was
also part of this operation so Steve
came and gave me this story he said now
mayor we're going to do this twin and
you're going to lead this and I'm like
you realize we had like a lot of
challenges in this town and I got a lot
of things to do and he said so you're
going to Ireland you're going with us do
you understand that this is really
important and I'm yes sir I I believe it
he said no no
no let me explain to you what the import
import is of Apple island of County Mayo
and he went through the history and
during the time that I was mayor um we
dedicated the um Monument to the potato
fam that's down on in the flats and told
that whole story and so it was you know
the story of the Irish coming to
Cleveland really seeking a better life
and seeking opportunity and he was like
we came here but we never forgot where
we came from and I need to take you I
need to take you and show you where we
were and and
so at some point you just have to open
your arms and say yes sir I'm going I'm
there so Steve mooy puts together like
75 clevelanders so I'm I'm leaving this
group of 70 you know I'm thinking it's
like me and Steve and Ann and maybe a
couple people oh no 75 people and we go
to AAL Island where I will report to you
that there are more people in Cleveland
who are from AAL Island and live in AAL
Island in AAL Island there are more
sheep and people um when you go into the
churches every stained glass window says
dedicated by gilan Sweeney and they're
all the names you know
from from home every ambulance and
rescue squad has a plaque on the side
that says donated by uh Kang Sweeny mooy
St Patrick's Church of Cleveland Ohio uh
and you I became this instant celebrity
which was quite an unusual situation um
for then they had beg PES follow me we
started the day with bag pipes
everywhere we went there were bag pipes
and seeing
Steve really building this and it was a
partnership that was not just a tourism
partnership it was not just an emotional
partnership it was really looking at how
do we build those bonds that are going
to last for a
lifetime and as we crossed the bridge
and did the formal signing ceremony it
was really an incredible moment for me
because I learned an awful lot about
Cleveland I learned an awful lot about
Steve I learned a awful lot about his
family and as we
were coming
home and Steve was not feeling fabulous
at the time um he had suffered um from
uh some kind of cancer lyoma that that
had hurt his uh vocal CS which was a big
deal because he always sang the Irish
Anthem and the American Anthem at the
beginning of the St Patrick's Day parade
and this had been a tradition forever
and so singing for him was really
important so we did the whole trip we
walked along uh we walked along the
shores of the west of Ireland and then
we were back at the airport getting
ready to
leave and we're sitting in this little
room in the
airport and all of us who' been on the
trip and Steves all of a sudden began to
sing and Annie his wife
said I don't think it's supposed to
sing and he looked at her and he said I
will sing and you know then some of us
were like well no we don't want anything
to happen to him and finally she says
let him enjoy let him have fun and I
want you to listen for a minute
everybody knows the lyrics he's saying
Danny Boy and we were all in tears and
just listen to the end of the
lyrics when he
says but when he come and all the
flowers are dying if I am dead as dead I
well may be you'll come and find the
place where I am lying and kneel and say
and I there for me and I shall hear the
soft you tread above me all my
grave will warm and sweeter be for you
will bend and tell me that you love me
and I shall sleep in peace until you
come to me we love
[Applause]
people